Guide to the Riggs family papers, 1839-1959 and undated RL.10061
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Riggs family papers
1839-1959 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Riggs family
RL.10061
4 Linear Feet
The Riggs family lived in Washington, D.C. George Washington Riggs was the founder of Riggs and Company and the Riggs National Bank. The collection contains correspondence, legal papers, financial papers, pictures, and printed material of the Riggs family of Washington, D.C. Correspondence relates to the interest of George Washington Riggs, founder of Riggs and Company and of the Riggs National Bank, in collecting art objects, currency, and paintings, and to his investments in Washington real estate and to the various investments of his children and grandchildren. Legal papers relate principally to the settlement of the estates of various members of the family. Financial papers relate chiefly to Alice and Jane Riggs, daughters of G. W. Riggs, and a few bills of exchange. Printed materials include inaugural souvenirs representing the Cleveland through the Coolidge administrations. Among the pictures are photographs of the Riggs sisters, and autographed photographs belonging to G. W. Riggs.
Biographical note
The Riggs family lived in Washington, D.C. George Washington Riggs was the founder of Riggs and Company and the Riggs National Bank.
Provenance
The Riggs family papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a in 1971.
Collection Overview
This collection contains correspondence, legal papers, financial papers, pictures, and printed material of the Riggs family. Correspondence pertains to the interest of George Washington Riggs (1813-1881), founder of Riggs and Company and of the Riggs National Bank, Washington, D.C., in collecting art objects, currency, and paintings, and to his investments in Washington real estate; the investments of his daughters, Jane Riggs (1853-1930) and Alice Riggs, in various companies; the settlement of the share of the estate of Katherine Shedden (Riggs) de Geofroy (d. 1881) belonging to her sons, George de Geofroy and Antoine de Geofroy; business correspondence between Jane Riggs and the children of Cecilia (Riggs) and Henry Howard, especially George Howard; and the stranding of Jane Riggs in Germany at the outbreak of World War I.
Legal papers, relating principally to the settlement of the estates of various members of the Riggs family, include estate papers of Elisha Riggs (1779-1853); will of George Washington Riggs, records of the division of the estate, and an accounting of the executor, Lawrason Riggs (1814-1888), brother of George Washington Riggs; papers pertaining to the lawsuit of Francis B. Riggs, William C. Riggs, and Mary G. Riggs, of the family of Elisha Riggs, Jr., against the remaining members of families of the children of Elisha Riggs, Sr., containing a listing of the members of the Riggs family and several wills; inventory of the estate of Thomas Lawrason Riggs, 1888; inventory of the estate of Jane Riggs, 1930-1931; guardianship papers for George de Geofroy and Antoine de Geofroy, 1893-1894; and title to a real estate lot in Washington, D.C., a legal matter involving former President Franklin Pierce.
Financial papers are chiefly the statements of Alice and Jane Riggs, and a few bills of exchange relating to the commercial transactions of George Peabody and his partner, Elisha Riggs. Printed materials include pamphlets on the suit of Elisha Francis Riggs (d. 1936) against Mary McMullen, companion of Jane Riggs, for possession of family treasures; and invitations and inaugural souvenirs from the White House representing the Cleveland through the Coolidge administrations. Among the pictures are photographs of the Riggs sisters, and autographed photographs belonging to George Washington Riggs, including those of the British commissioners who settled the Alabama claims in 1871.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Washington (D.C.) -- Social life and customs; Washington (D.C.) -- Economic conditions; Presidents -- United States -- Inauguration; Art -- Collectors and collecting -- United States; Inheritance and succession -- Washington (D.C.); Executors and administrators -- Washington (D.C.); Real estate investment -- Washington (D.C.); Riggs, George Washington; Riggs family
- Riggs family papers, 1839-1959 and undated
  - Family tree, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1840-1919 (Box 1)
  - Legal Papers: Estates, 1853-1881 (Box 1)
  - Legal Papers: Estates, 1884-1931 (Box 1)
  - Legal Papers Concerning Lot Number 9, 1883-1885 (Box 1)
  - Legal Papers Regarding the Guardianship of George and Antoine De Geofroy, 1893-1896 (Box 1)
  - Financial Papers: Jane A. Riggs Accounts, 1912-1924 (Box 1)
  - Jane Riggs Financial Statements and Papers, 1885-1911; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Financial Papers, 1839-1893 (Box 2)
  - Alice L. Riggs Financial Statements, 1898-1927 (Box 2)
  - Printed Material, 1894-Circa 1913 (Box 2)
  - Cards and Invitations, 1885-1925; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1881-1923 and undated (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Furnishings from the Home of George W. Riggs on I Street (Duplicates from McMullen papers), 1936, 1953-1959 and undated (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Riggs Family and Various Foreign Dignitaries, 1864-1870s and undated (Box 2)
  - Financial Papers, Legal Papers Concerning Lot 9, Legal Papers: Estates, 1882-1888 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Printed Material, Photograph of Furnishings from the Home of George Riggs, 1867 and undated (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Landplot diagram, undated (Oversize-folder 3)